hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and today we are
going to talk about an interesting
feature which could be useful for you
during your automation
now consider that you are working on a
desktop application and before you
launch that application you want to make
sure that all the other programs which
are open uh in your desktop are closed
okay so you want to start up clean and
you want to close all other programs
which are currently open before running
your automated test just to make sure
that it is not interrupted by any other
program right and that could be anything
that program could be a browser that
program could be a notepad or that
program could even be your Tosca
Commander or some something else right
so all of this can be done using the
t-box Start program module
now we have seen how we can use debug
Start program module to start different
programs like notepad browsers or any
other application but you can use the
same module to close those programs also
right so don't go uh by the name of the
Tosca t-box automation module it can be
used to do both the things which is to
open and close programs now we have
already seen how we can open different
programs using this today we are going
to see how we can close programs using
this particular module so to demonstrate
this I'm going to use three different
cases first we are going to look at how
we can close the browsers and then we
are going to look at how we can close
the Notepad application and then we'll
see how we can even close the Tosca
Commander if it's open in the background
okay so the first step is to add the
t-box automation module okay so let's go
to search and ADD test step and here we
are going to search for t-box Start
program
okay which is a process operation and
then we will add this module here right
now we have already seen this earlier
that you can pass the path of the
application and then it will start that
particular program right but what if I
want to close the program I don't need
to give the path of the application
otherwise it is going to open the
program right so for this purpose we are
going to use one of the programs or
commands which are available with
Microsoft itself okay and that is called
the task kill command okay so in this
particular task skill it can end uh one
or more tasks or processes which are
running in your Windows machine right
and this processes can be ended by
either the process ID or the image name
okay
now there are some parameters which you
need to pass for this and specifically
we'll be using the image name okay of
the process to be terminated
also will be looking at how we can
specify the process to be forcefully
ended okay so this will make sure that
all the remote processes are forcefully
ended so these are the two arguments uh
which will be passing on uh when we are
using this particular command Okay so
let's go ahead and now see how we can do
this in the t-box Start program module
okay so here to start off we need to
enter task kill in the path okay so this
will make sure that it is going to open
this particular command okay from the
windows so we need to mention task skill
here and along with that we need to
enter some arguments right so which are
the parameters which we looked upon
earlier right so for this
um we'll first mention slash IM which is
image name and we are going to mention
the exact image name of the process
which is currently running right
so uh if I open google.com here and the
other URL right so I've got multiple
tabs open here and if I go to my Windows
Task Manager okay and here in the
processes you will see all the apps
which are running so if I go to Google
Chrome and I go here and go to details
so this is the PID which we are
referring to earlier
and this is the image name okay so if
you are using image name you have to use
uh the name here which is displayed in
the details for that particular process
okay and for the Chrome browser it is
chrome.exe
so the same I will mention it here which
is Chrome dot EXE
and also We'll add another parameter
here which is slash F which is going to
force all the processes to run which has
got this particular image name right so
these are the three parameters or
arguments which you can add in your
t-box Start program along with the task
of value in the path okay and this will
basically close all the programs uh
which is related to the Chrome browser
okay
so let's go ahead and run this test case
now
and you will see uh it already ran the
program so it started task kill with the
following arguments which is slash
imchrome.exe F okay and in the
background you will see that Chrome
browser is already closed so I don't
have any programs uh or any web pages
which are open in the Chrome browser and
the Chrome browser itself is not open
okay so this is how you can basically
close your browsers using the t-box
Start program module okay
similarly uh you can do the same for
other programs as well right so if I add
the t-box Start program again right you
can also copy paste it from the previous
test case right again I need to use task
kill here and in the arguments I'm going
to use uh slash F to force it and then
slash IM okay
and then I need to find out uh
what is the program name for this
notepad plus plus right so I go to task
manager and I go to processes uh here
there is notepad plus plus so I'll go to
details
and this is the name notepad plus plus
dot exe right
so I'm going to write the same here
notepad plus plus dot exe and that's
going to close the Notepad application
okay so if I run this now
it's going to force close it okay so if
you don't give the force argument if you
are going to close it without the force
argument then you may uh get a pop-up
saying do you want to save this
particular program right so it's always
safe to use this argument whenever
you're trying to close any particular
application okay
and similarly we can also do it for
Tosca Commander okay so this is our last
case let's do that again quickly
so t-box Start program
and share again task kill
argument slash F
and then here we will give slash IM
and let's try and find out what is the
process name for this Tosca Commander
right
so here you can see there are so many
processes which are running and if I go
to some process
here
okay and go to details
so this is tosser commander.exe right
so Tosca Commander
dot EXE
okay so this is going to close my Tosca
Commander but if you're doing this make
sure you save everything okay
now in usual scenarios this may not be
required I mean you will never try to
close Tosca command.exe right but in
some scenarios if you are maybe running
um a batch file right which opens
um the Tosca commander and runs some
tests using the TC shell right so in
these cases maybe you want to close the
Tosca Commander itself right so this
could be useful in these kind of
scenarios
so I've saved uh whatever changes I have
done uh and let's go ahead and try to
close this Tosca Commander itself
okay and you can see that in the
background Tosca Commander was closed
okay
so that's how you can basically close
any program using the task kill command
which is a Windows command available
either you can use the process ID or you
can use the process name for the program
which you are trying to close okay so
it's a very powerful automation module
which you should be aware of whenever
you are working on any particular
automation
so that's all for this video hopefully
you enjoyed it
um and you learned something new today
uh don't forget to subscribe to our
Channel as we'll be posting a lot of
different videos
um on Tosca and also other automation
tools very soon
so until we meet again keep watching our
videos and do let us know if you want to
see any particular video on any
particular topic
huh